hello my name is Greta welcome back to
another episode of hermit craft I've
actually taken a step back I deleted all
of the work that I did on the top here
because the shape was a bit wrong I've
been experimenting in my creative world
and I need a little more time to nail
this because this season I want to
challenge myself on the build that I'm
going to be doing for my base and let me
just briefly explain why so I want to
really challenge myself by doing some
diagonals but this diagonal is actually
not too difficult what I want to do is a
two diagonal like this and the problem
with this is when you start trying to
detail it things start getting very very
challenging so I'm almost gonna have to
do my whole base in creative mode before
I even start trying to make it here
in other news over here I've got an
accidental iron farm I seriously every
time I log on there's more iron golems
than I can possibly cope with and I
honestly don't know what to do anymore
there's just too many of them I can take
care of them like this but if I if I
I've had many deaths to these guys so
I'm gonna play it safe and just get a
bucket of lava I'm sorry I and golems
you just you're just you're just all up
in my role as a mumbo jumbo this is a
casual number in my crops what's he
doing
[Laughter]
he must have just been like oh really
bought good time to come and visit me I
think I scared him away by burning my
friends what does he want
yes he's dropped us another sapling
hermit challenges now and he's gone
he's off I'll be back for you guys later
now I've got to remember the way to get
there you know you can just send a
message in chap
this is how much challenges okay next
time I got a challenge for you it's
gonna be the most ridiculous way of
letting you know possible it's gonna be
crazy
all right well okay speaking of
challenges I think you safe to say I
mean look at me first off look at me
yeah did you get good looking looking
good looking good
hang on I've got stuff to show you look
I've done that look at this
I've also got this I don't know if this
counts but I mean look technically
permit challenge rules state that
ringing the bell means that you accept
that I've completed the challenge all
right and that's fine
I also was half expecting you just to
kidnap okay I will I will thoroughly
accept that you've got good you got a
lot of stuff here you've painted
yourself out beacon and do I need to
show you the doors that I've got well
first you have to ring this bell you
have to ring the bell to say that I've
completed the challenge as I say you
technically already did ring a bell but
I think this is the specific Bell okay
it really pains me I could see I could
see the hesitation all right like well
I've seen that you've removed my doors
which actually almost make me come under
stuck this morning when I came
downstairs and there was just a creeper
in the bottom right here
I've been labeling I've been labeling
the doors admittedly most of the doors
that I have belonged to scar there's no
one there's scar three and four
they're scarred or one and then I've got
another fall from sky which he hasn't
laid which I haven't labeled yet so I've
got about eight doors from Scarfo what's
going on like I suppose I know what's
going on so it's kind of a little bit
more predictable all right well I'm
fairly satisfied that you have been
there so I have to stop now I can stop
now no no no remember it's the whole
season but I'm satisfied with your
progress I guess we'll do like a
progress up there every month or so you
know all right dude well I mean it's a
it's been fun how much challenges
everything's gone successfully I'm
feeling good and I will look out for any
saplings that you drop down to me or
anything like that when you want to
challenge me to anything else but anyway
yeah it's been it's been cool yeah
things wrap up real fast with how much
challenges we just kind of as soon as
we've rang the bells it's like see I
don't want to talk to you very much so
the challenge is bro initiation this
hermit challenge thing is actually
really really strange that mumbos come
up with and I've actually got a few
ideas for him later down the line but
I've got something more pressing to deal
with in today's episode I've had a go in
creative and I've actually designed my
base but it means redoing all of this
and I now have a good idea so I've made
a big old list of everything I'm going
to have to get now there's one big issue
and it's that one dark prismarine going
to be an absolute nightmare but I've
already made some headway I have found
myself couple of sheep which we are
going to use to make a quick automatic
sheep shearing farm now I've never
actually made one of these before but I
imagine it's fairly easy to do you need
a place for your sheep which I think
will be here you need a dispenser for
the shears you need to detect when that
block there changes so imagine you can
do something like this I need a
collection system
underneath as well think that is I think
that's it I think that is all you have
to do I'm not entirely sure we'll need
to pop one sheep in here just to make
sure you have been chosen Oh No all
right maybe we'll play this a little bit
safer there we go
so that should basically do the trick
but I'm obviously gonna need more than
just one sheep because this is gonna
take a year and a half so I'm gonna keep
breeding these sheep and I'm gonna get
all of these guys set up so bear with me
and maybe I'll even record it
[Music]
I managed to get a couple of hours of
afk in and let's see how we've done the
sheep are still being shared and we have
made some decent wool profits this is
gonna go a long way I've also managed to
collect a bunch of items up here as you
can see I've been organizing everything
on some stone blah blah blah we have got
stuff I am actually in a place where I
can start laying down the foundations of
my base however there is something very
important that it's about to happen on
the hermit craft server basically bedlam
everyone is going to turn against each
other
very very soon and I'm about to explain
why but for that we need to go to the
shopping district and then we need to
come back here to explain it I've
created a I get so lost in here I've
created a dirt path to my vase I might I
might do something a little bit better
but I actually think this is kind of
funny right to the shopping district now
the reason that the server is going to
go into a full-out war is this game over
here the head game by zombie plio
we are actually going to opt-in but I'm
gonna have to explain it so you can see
there's multiple Hermits names here s
cow tango green tinfoil chef Kevin
everyone and the idea is you have to
collect their head like these like the
cow like the spider like Ren's head
everyone now you acquire these by
killing them by killing the other
Hermits with your sword or you can buy
them from wandering traders you just
have to get your hands on their head and
you can get points based on how many
heads you get the ones at the top are
worth more so let's have a look at this
book welcome to the head game and the
reward is 32 diamond blocks that would
go a long way to win the diamonds you
must opt into PvP and the head game will
begin at 5 p.m. on the 20th that's in
like a few hours by the way so I am very
very late to signing up so the first
head you bring in is 10 points then 6
then 3 and then everyone after that is 1
point
mob heads are 1 each as well dragon
heads a turn so you can do this without
doing PvP
I want to participate so I'm going to
take my sign and I'm gonna pop it over
here I don't think there's actually any
price to sign up at all it's free to
enter you literally just yeah you just
you'd let's just sign up and that's it
so clear is just giving away free
diamonds she must really want all of
these minecraft heads this also means
that I'm signing up for PvP so as you
can tell there's gonna be a lot of PvP
going on on the hermit craft server
which is gonna be a lot of fun and I'm
about to make it worse so much worse the
head game is going to be a lot of fun
collecting all the different Hermits
heads in various different ways
but I'm gonna make it even better now
that you understand the head game we
need to go back to my base so I can tell
you why this is gonna get worse
do you remember last season last season
I introduced a game called tag and guess
what tag is back it's bigger it's bigger
it's better and it's going to cause
mayhem this time and this is called the
rather inventive name tag to electric
Boogaloo and there is a rule you cannot
refer to tag as anything other than tag
to electric Boogaloo in full okay so in
tag to electric Boogaloo you have to
keep the tag on you at all times
same as last time but here's the thing
we've actually got a data pack on the
server that's a little bit of technology
that's going to track who has the tag
here's the thing I want to keep the tag
the goal of tag to electric Boogaloo is
to keep it if I press tab you can see
everyone's score is currently set to 0
the longer I hold on to this tag the
more my score goes up every hour I get a
point so to win tag 2 electric Boogaloo
I need to get 250 points on the tab list
50 hours in my inventory online on the
server I have to be online to get a
point now how do people get tagged to
electric boogaloo from me
well anyway they want literally anyway
now they have to opt into this game
because obviously it's got PvP involved
and not everyone wants PvP so we need to
go back to the shopping district and set
this up now everyone on the server
already knows about this game I've
explained it behind the scenes so all
there is to do is create a place where
they can sign up and get any additional
information that they need so I told
everyone that I was going to make a
little space for people to sign up and
it's not a shot this is just a temporary
game there is an end to it unlike last
season there will be a winner and the
winner will get the diamonds the cost to
enter is one diamond block and I've
renamed it green so everyone knows who's
opt-in and who isn't you won't know who
has the tag until you see their score
going up so later in the game it might
be actually quite difficult to know
who's actually tagged good luck to all
of you figuring out who has it so I'm
gonna write down all the information
really quickly tag to electric Boogaloo
please use the full name welcome to tag
- electric Boogaloo the aim of the game
is to hold the tag for as many in-game
hours as possible
one hour equals one point on the tab
lists the first 50 points wins all the
diamonds you can get the tag by any
means necessary PvP trickery bribery
traps or selling you can even afk but
obviously that makes you a sitting duck
rename a diamond block to enter
hopefully that is about as simple as you
get like I said I've explained this to
all the hermit's behind the scenes so
hopefully they understand this is just
the place where they can enter into the
game and I now officially declare tag -
electric Boogaloo begun this ties in so
well with Cleo's game hermits come get
me come get the tag I dare ya
I'm gonna I'm gonna get so many diamonds
I'm gonna get so many diamonds I'm gonna
get I'm gonna get all the diamonds from
this I'm gonna get all the divers from
that actually probably not I'm really
quite bad at PvP alright now that we've
got the minigames out of the way the
server events that have already begun
within a few weeks of the sir
starting head game and tag to electric
boogaloo synergize very very well
because if you kill someone not only
will they drop the tag they will also
drop their player head so there's a lot
of incentive for crazy crazy PvP alright
let's go back to the base because we've
actually got some some work to do now
that I've just announced that the server
is going into a a full-on conflict it's
it's time we get some work done I've
also got something really really funny
to show you so some friends of mine over
at element animation they do some pretty
funny voice impressions for the villager
now I've been kind of doing the same
thing like where's the brood where's the
brood and they actually kindly have
agreed to make a resource pack for me or
they already have made the resource pack
for me making the villagers talk rather
than her the problem is it didn't work
exactly how I expected but I'm gonna put
it on anyway and show you you see the
issue is it that there's too many of
them so they just spam hello at me so if
I trade with this guy they also have
custom sounds for when they talk to you
so yeah I I have added this resource
back but I don't know if we can keep it
on because they literally just just
constantly hello hello hello hello
there's even there's even like custom
death noises and everything let's get
rid of a villager that we don't want I'm
not gonna be able to get my stuff back
what have I done please forgive me
oh come on through the window
I've died three times and everyone's
just so desensitized to it no one cares
anymore okay okay is there a way for me
to get in grab my stuff
angry at me no I think this day like
great I could get I can run it how no
way no how did they do that I'm in
trouble I'm gonna lose my stuff all of
these golems angry at me these guys
they're just they're just guarding my
stuff like no you're not getting it back
come on okay this might be the only way
I'm at a safe distance
you're gonna guard my stuff forever
[Music]
everything went so badly hello hello and
they're all giving me bad trades where
did they all go guys go back to your bed
no no come on no come on leave me be
leave me be
please okay come on these guys are
blocking me from my own base okay I need
to get these villages back to their room
seriously oh come on really leave me
alone these iron golems are such a pain
I think I've just got to wait for night
now I'll come on oh sorry
as soon as it hits night they should go
back into their house because they need
to go to bed I should also mention that
this tag is actually a custom-made item
it can't be replicated so if you just
renamed a tag - tag - electric Boogaloo
it wouldn't work it has to be this exact
one and if it's lost in lava or
something it's replaced by the system so
this is a really really cool way of
doing a server game now just everyone go
back to bed have a Sun is setting but
she'll be going back to bed soon is that
everyone is every
and present and accounted for hello
hello no no no no bed bed bed bed bed
bed bed bed it's bedtime bedtime there
we go looks like everyone's here we
didn't have a couple of casualties but
we didn't lose any of our valuable
traders Oh what are you guys doing he
literally fell into bed I think we're
good I think it's safe I think we can
sleep
you know I've been collecting heads here
for a little while look look at all
these I've got some I got some points
behind me I don't know if I want to give
them away I like having a collection of
these also I saw this earlier but I
haven't had a chance to look at it
because I was so busy explaining tag to
electric boogaloo okay right let's have
a look at what we've got here hey g-man
thank you for saving me the other day
here is an invitation to the diamond
challenge mine you can use the right
tunnel for branch mining beacon mining
area coming soon also here is 8:00
flight box scar ah yay rook I mean I've
already got lots of rockets we kind of
went halfsies on it but you know that's
nice is there's a lot of crafting to get
that up so what's this diamond mine ciao
I mean there's so many challenges and
games and death happening on the server
I mean I've been here before but I
haven't actually sadly read anything
there's absolutely no information on
what the diamond mine challenge is ska I
need I'm gonna need some info bro
there's one time helpless there's one
sign that says the diamond mine
challenge what and there's just nothing
ska
i'ma find out what this is about but
Skaar come on dude I've had the tag for
nearly an hour so we're about to see if
our data pack for this game works
hopefully I will get my first point soon
also if people sign up to take to
electric boogaloo they fully understand
that there might be casualties
some people might lose their items some
people will probably die I will probably
die and everyone that signs up is a-okay
with that so
hopefully this will be a lot of fun but
just remember that PvP is allowed and
it's probably gonna get quite hairy
hello
also thank you to element animation for
putting this resource pack together I
don't know whether I'm gonna keep it on
let me know in the comments down below
hello I always forget about it as well
there will be a link in the description
to element animations channel for
Hertford for doing this for me I'll just
let everyone know that they can now sign
up I'm still waiting for my first point
to take over it should be any second now
I hope scar and I really need to
decorate this we can bleed too dark
Reaper farm but we've kind of just left
it going it's actually been really
really successful check it out look at
all this gunpowder and also a lot of
string now string wasn't something that
we really wanted in this farm but we got
it and so I might as well use it look at
all this I might as well use this to
craft up some wool cuz I'm gonna need it
for my build anyway forget the sheep
farm look at this look how many stacks
of gangue that is that is several stacks
of wool that we got there so I mean look
at this
this is gunpowder for days I'm gonna
talk to Skaar about opening a rocket
shop because we've got all the tools
necessary and the farms necessary to
sell them and we know that Rockets sell
well I've held on to the tag now for
nearly an hour I must be getting my
point very very soon while we're waiting
for the first point to take over what I
want to do is actually get alerted when
mumbo sends me a message so I think what
I'm gonna do is just extend this out a
little bit and have it so when it comes
over on a detector rail it's gonna make
this Bell here go pending bidding
bidding hopefully this is quite simple
it's just a case of adding a
observer clock here so it should be as
simple as detecting this piston pushes
and in it goes into the Bell I think it
is as simple as that
Gris and learning redstone what a
terrifying thing well that will keep
going off until I answer the mail from
mumbo that's absolutely brilliant I love
it let's actually send a bit of mail
some mumbo I haven't sent him anything
in a while now he must be wondering
where I've gone I'm just
gonna confuse him by saying tag to
electric Boogaloo so tag to electric
Boogaloo
off you go message to mumbo sin and now
I've got an alarm bell system for when I
get a message also I saw this really
cool detailing trick on an Instagram
post so what you do is you put an item
frame down you then put any block maybe
a darker one of some kind I'm going to
use dark oak planks for this and then
you can like right-click it and then you
add a lantern underneath so it looks
that's a really nice detail looks like
it's like hanging from that block I
think it would work probably better with
cyan terracotta or something so it
matches the iron but either way that's
just such a really neat little detail
hey we got our first point there we go
tag tag two electric boogaloo has
officially begun one point two green and
I'm afraid that is where we're going to
have to leave today's episode obviously
a lot of things are about to happen
so next episode should be or could be
very dangerous but for now I'm gonna get
working on this bass here because I've
got some resources and I'm itching to
get started so I will see you in the
next episode good-bye-ee 1.2 me 49 to go